Guide to the Kilpatrick Collection of Cherokee Manuscripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Notebook #10: "Uwedasat Vol II 18-24"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 940)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 941)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 942)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 943)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 944)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 945)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 946)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 947)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 948)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 949)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 950)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 951)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 952)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 953)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 954)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 955)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 956)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 957)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 958)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 959)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 960)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 961)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 962)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 963)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 964)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 965)
  - Medical formula, 1922 May (Box 11, Folder 966)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 11, Folder 967)
  - Medical formula, 1926 July 21 (Box 11, Folder 968)
- Notebook #11: "Henry Watt"
  - Kilpatrick Notebook cover, "11, Henry Watt", undated (Box 11, Folder 969)
  - Christie, Ned. Medical formula, 1802 (Box 11, Folder 970)
  - Obituary, 1900 October 12 (Box 11, Folder 971)
  - US Registration Certificate for William Campbell of Barber OK (in English), 1917 June 5 (Box 11, Folder 972)
  - Recto: Letter; Verso: Syllabary practice, undated (Box 11, Folder 973)
  - Printed bill to Mr. John Campbell (in English), 1919 October 1 (Box 11, Folder 974)
  - Awigadoga, Tsegsini (Standingdeer, Jackson). Letter to John Campbell, 1914 January 29 (Box 11, Folder 975)
  - Unidentified document, undated (Box 11, Folder 976)
  - List of meetings and participants, 1881 April 16 (Box 11, Folder 977)
  - Obituary, 1901 April 17 (Box 11, Folder 978)
  - Didagw(i). Personal letter, 1893 (Box 11, Folder 979)
    Translated in Shadow, p.45
  - List; community, circa 1895 (Box 11, Folder 980)
  - Unidentified note, syllabary practice, circa 1887 (Box 11, Folder 981)
  - Syllabary practice, undated (Box 11, Folder 982)
  - Unidentified note, undated (Box 11, Folder 983)
  - List of names and dates, circa 1876 (Box 11, Folder 984)
  - Recto: Unidentified note; Verso: Syllabary, 1885 (Box 11, Folder 985)
  - Recto: Envelope addressed to Henry Watt (Henila Wadi); Verso: Unidentified note, 1907 May 8 (Box 11, Folder 986)
  - Financial record, undated (Box 11, Folder 987)
  - Recto: Unidentifed community document; Verso: list of names, 1894 (Box 11, Folder 988)
  - Locust, Jackson (Tsunulvhvsgi Gvlewisgi). Letter, 1909 December 26 (Box 11, Folder 989)
  - Standingdeer, David (Dewi Awigadoga). Letter to Uwedasadi (John Campbell), 1923 December 7 (Box 11, Folder 990)
    Translated in Shadow, p. 72
  - Watt, Henry. Letter to Theodore Roosevelt (in English), 1905 January (Box 11, Folder 991)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Henry Watt letter from coll."
  - Wadi, Henilv (Henry Watt). Letter, 1903 December 10 (Box 11, Folder 992)
  - Letter, begins "denili wadi ginali" (Daniel Watt you and friends), 1905 January 2 (Box 11, Folder 993)
  - Golanvsdi. Letter to Daniel Watt, undated (Box 11, Folder 994)
  - Contract, 1894 December 31 (Box 11, Folder 995)
    Translated in Shadow, p. 47
  - Letter to Daniel Watt, 1904 March 27 (Box 11, Folder 996)
  - Tsani Golasquai. Letter to Henry Watt, 1907 August 17 (Box 11, Folder 997)
  - Tsani Golasquai. Letter to Henry Watt, 1903 August 17 (Box 11, Folder 998)
  - Tsani Golasquai. Letter to Henry Watt, 1900 May 18 (Box 11, Folder 999)
  - Tsani Golasquai. Letter to Henry Watt, 1903 December 6 (Box 11, Folder 1000)
  - Tsani Golasquai. Letter to Henry Watt, 1903 November 11 (Box 11, Folder 1001)
  - Tsowa. Letter to Henry Watt, 1915 March 16 (Box 11, Folder 1002)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand; "Henili Wati [?] Collection".
  - Financial record, undated (Box 11, Folder 1003)
  - Account of runaway teenager, 1902 June 8 (Box 11, Folder 1004)
    Translated in Shadow, pp. 54-55
  - Watt family children names, 1864 (Box 11, Folder 1004a)
  - Historical note, 1888 July 7 (Box 11, Folder 1005)
  - Obituary, after 1884 (Box 11, Folder 1006)
  - Financial record, undated (Box 11, Folder 1007)
  - Birth record for William Blackbird, after 1904 February 7 (Box 11, Folder 1008)
  - Journal or note, 1912 (Box 11, Folder 1009)
  - Tsowa. Letter, 1904 June 19 (Box 11, Folder 1010)
  - Journal, undated (Box 11, Folder 1011)
  - Obituary, after 1906 (Box 11, Folder 1012)
  - Recto: Journal; Verso: Unidentified note, 1917 February 2 (Box 11, Folder 1013)
  - Journal or note, undated (Box 11, Folder 1014)
  - Saloli Gowelvga (Squirrel, Ben). Business letter, 1904 August 3 (Box 11, Folder 1015)
  - Historical, 1904 January 12 (Box 11, Folder 1016)
  - Historical chronology, 1866 October 23 (Box 11, Folder 1017)
  - Business or Historical record, 1867 August 2 (Box 11, Folder 1018)
  - Prayer, 1910 October 2 (Box 11, Folder 1019)
  - Typed letter to John Comingdeer with handwritten response (in English), 1911 May 12 (Box 11, Folder 1020)
  - Recto: Unidentified note; Verso: Financial record, circa 1899 (Box 11, Folder 1021)
  - Unidentified journal or note, 1892 September 14 (Box 12, Folder 1022)
  - Medical formula, 1882 (Box 12, Folder 1023)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Klptrck note Matt Beaver Coll. (July 1963) 2 in autograph of gugonvda gadoga."
  - Medical formula, 1882 (Box 12, Folder 1024)
  - Unidentified journal or note, 1901 (Box 12, Folder 1025)
  - Historical note, undated (Box 12, Folder 1026)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1027)
    A variant of the formula in Box 12 folder 1028
  - Medical formula, 1898 December 14 (Box 12, Folder 1028)
    Translated in Shadow, p. 48-50
    A variant of the formula in Box 12 folder 1027
  - Medical formula, 1882 June (Box 12, Folder 1029)
  - Medical formula, 1882 June 19 (Box 12, Folder 1030)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Saedga Egi Coll."
  - Medical formula, 1882 June (Box 12, Folder 1031)
  - Medical formula, 1882 June 8 (Box 12, Folder 1032)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1033)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1034)
  - Township meeting minutes, 1861 July 15 (Box 12, Folder 1035)
    Found with two notes in Jack Kilpatrick's hand: 1) Recto: "Anigiduwagi Records obtained from Snow Adair 1962 1862-1869"; Verso: "(IL No. 146 Commentary)" 2) "Author sqnd."
  - Bible verse citations, undated (Box 12, Folder 1036)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1037)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1038)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1039)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1040)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1041)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1042)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1043)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1044)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1045)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1046)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1047)
  - Medical formula or practice, undated (Box 12, Folder 1048)
  - Recto: Writing practice; Verso: Hymn, undated (Box 12, Folder 1049)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1050)
  - Flute, Sam. Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1051)
  - Flute, Sam. Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1052)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1053)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1054)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1055)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Collection XXV (probably 19th century)"; Also found with note in unidentified hand, "Bauer Lot 326".
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1056)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1057)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Collection XXVI (signed by Dagvya, 1863)".
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1058)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Collection XXVII (19th Century)".
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1059)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1060)
  - Medical formula notebook, undated (Box 12, Folder 1061)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uyvtloyi Digi father of Will Dick"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1062)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1063)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1064)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1065)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1066)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1067)
  - Medical formula, circa 1880 (Box 12, Folder 1068)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1069)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1070)
  - Recto: Medical formula; Verso: Financial record, circa 1862 (Box 12, Folder 1071)
  - Medical formula, 1881 (Box 12, Folder 1072)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1073)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1074)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1075)
  - Medical formula or chant, undated (Box 12, Folder 1076)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat Collection XXVIII (large sheets, in ink; not by Uwedasat)".
  - Medical formula (Box 12, Folder 1077)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1078)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' Collection XXIX (on cardboard and wrapping paper)"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1079)
  - Unidentified note, 1897 August 6 (Box 12, Folder 1080)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1081)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1082)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat XXXII"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1083)
  - Letter, 1890 May 31 (Box 12, Folder 1084)
  - Letter, 1891 January 4 (Box 12, Folder 1085)
    Translated in Shadow, pp. 44-45
  - Letter, 1908 December 29 (Box 12, Folder 1086)
    Translated in Shadow, p. 59
  - Golatsusdii. Letter to Dvnadedoni, 1893 April 22 (Box 12, Folder 1087)
  - Recto: Letter, Verso: Note, 1881 August 29 (Box 12, Folder 1088)
    Recto: Translated in Shadow, pp. 34-35
- Notebook #5
  - Kilpatrick notebook cover, "5", undated (Box 12, Folder 1089)
  - Unidentified note, undated (Box 12, Folder 1090)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1091)
  - Notebook with medical formula, financial records, circa 1935 (Box 12, Folder 1092)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand "Uwedasat' record Books"
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1093)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1094)
  - Recto: Note, on election ballot; Verso: Note on English grammar, after 1940 August 5 (Box 12, Folder 1095)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1096)
  - Medical formula, undated (Box 12, Folder 1097)
  - Unesdala notebook; financial records, hymns, circa 1949 (Box 12, Folder 1098)
    Found with 2 notes in Jack Kilpatrick's hand; 1) "diganiyisgi nvya 3 record books" 2) "Unestala record book"
  - Journal notebook, circa 1935 (Box 12, Folder 1099)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Adelagatiyasgada Collection"
  - Journal and financial notebook, circa 1935 (Box 12, Folder 1100)
  - Hummingbird, Dick (Adelagadiya). Echota church financial record, circa 1959 (Box 12, Folder 1101)
    Found with two notes in Jack Kilpatrick's hand; 1) "Treasurer's Records Echota Church, 1959 Dick Hummingbird Treasurer" 2) "Adelagatiya Sycamore Tree Sunday School Record"
  - Journal notebook, circa 1937 (Box 12, Folder 1102)
  - Unesdala notebook; committee minutes, hymn, circa 1938 (Box 13, Folder 1103)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand "Unestala Book (Anikituwagi Records) 1938"
  - Nvtsi Newadv. Journal or note, bible citation, undated (Box 13, Folder 1104)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Nûtsi Newadû Document III"
  - Nofire, Jack. Hymn book, 1939 March 10 (Box 13, Folder 1105)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Richard Glory - Sam O'Field Hymn Book (in handwriting of Jack Nofire)"
  - Nvtsi Newadv. Bible citation and translation, undated (Box 13, Folder 1106)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Nûtsi Newadû Document I"
  - Nvtsi Newadv. Bible citation and translation, undated (Box 13, Folder 1107)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Nûtsi Newadû Document II"
  - Echota church financial records, circa 1961 (Box 13, Folder 1108)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Echota Church Treasurer's Records"
  - Prayer, undated (Box 13, Folder 1109)
  - Hymn book, undated (Box 13, Folder 1110)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Hymn book (obtained from Sequoia Leach)"
  - Acorn, John. Letter, 1916 June 30 (Box 13, Folder 1111)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "John Acorn Collection"
  - Acorn, John. Financial record or note, circa 1916 (Box 13, Folder 1112)
  - Cherokee Republican Constitution, undated (Box 13, Folder 1113)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Cherokee Republican Constitution. Found in the effects of Unestala in 1962"
  - Uwedasat. Financial records, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 1114)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Uwedasat' record book"
  - Rooster, Will. Church records, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 1115)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Wili Ayuya [Will Rooster] Church Records"
    Note in margin first page in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Will Rooster? Found on the road by Willie Jumper, 1961"
  - Washington, George. Myths notebook, undated (Box 13, Folder 1116)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "George Washington Notebook (myths)"
- Notebook #15
  - Kilpatrick notebook cover, "15", undated (Box 13, Folder 1117)
  - Community letter, ends "otsikamiti", 1929 June 17 (Box 13, Folder 1118)
  - Letter or journal, 1926 July (Box 13, Folder 1119)
  - Financial record, undated (Box 13, Folder 1120)
  - Unidentified note, 1929 March 2 (Box 13, Folder 1121)
  - Receipt or Financial record, 1928 May 3 (Box 13, Folder 1122)
  - Church record, 1926 June 19 (Box 13, Folder 1123)
  - Recto: Prayer; Verso: List of names, undated (Box 13, Folder 1124)
  - Recto: Church record; Verso: List of names, 1926 June 20 (Box 13, Folder 1125)
  - Recto: List of names; Verso: Financial record, undated (Box 13, Folder 1126)
  - Recto: List of names; Verso: Financial record, undated (Box 13, Folder 1127)
  - Recto: Reciept (in English); Verso: Financial record, undated (Box 13, Folder 1128)
  - Obituary, 1931 May 16 (Box 13, Folder 1129)
  - Hymn, "No. 18", undated (Box 13, Folder 1130)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Unesdala Collection I Hymns"
  - Hymn, "No. 38", undated (Box 13, Folder 1131)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1132)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1133)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1134)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1135)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1136)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1137)
    Hhymn is found in Cherokee Hymns 9th ed., p. 34
  - Unidentified note, undated (Box 13, Folder 1138)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1139)
  - List of names and hymns, 1947 July 19 (Box 13, Folder 1140)
  - Bible verses, undated (Box 13, Folder 1141)
  - Church service agenda, 1935 April 12 (Box 13, Folder 1142)
  - Hymn, begins "igatseli ugvwiyuhi galutsv", undated (Box 13, Folder 1143)
  - Hymn, "my soul sweet peace abounds", undated (Box 13, Folder 1145)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1144)
  - Hymn, "#10 in Perfect Peace", undated (Box 13, Folder 1146)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1147)
  - Hymn, "nalisgwadisvna", undated (Box 13, Folder 1148)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1149)
  - Hymn, "Wisgi uniyosgi", undated (Box 13, Folder 1150)
    Translated in Shadow, p. 82
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1151)
  - Hymn, "164", undated (Box 13, Folder 1152)
  - Hymns, "22" and "2nd verse No. 68", undated (Box 13, Folder 1153)
  - Hymn, "The wonder of messiah no. 158", undated (Box 13, Folder 1154)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1155)
  - Hymn, "No. 107 ani elohi", undated (Box 13, Folder 1156)
  - Hymn, begins "galvgwodiyu sunale", undated (Box 13, Folder 1157)
  - Hymn, "No. 34 Perfect Peace", undated (Box 13, Folder 1158)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1159)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1160)
  - Recto: Community note; Verso: List of committee members, 1938 April 30 (Box 13, Folder 1161)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1162)
  - Story, undated (Box 13, Folder 1163)
  - Hymn, "#133", undated (Box 13, Folder 1164)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1165)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1166)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1167)
  - Hymn, "164", undated (Box 13, Folder 1168)
  - Hymn with sheet music, undated (Box 13, Folder 1169)
  - Hymn, "if you love your mother no. 132", undated (Box 13, Folder 1170)
  - Hymn, "no. 41", undated (Box 13, Folder 1171)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1172)
  - Hymn, "#38", undated (Box 13, Folder 1173)
  - Hymn, "no. 60", undated (Box 13, Folder 1174)
  - Hymn, "Leading Lights no 80 Spring Time in Glory", undated (Box 13, Folder 1175)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1176)
    Found with unidentified torn scrap of paper
  - Hymn, "98:10", undated (Box 13, Folder 1177)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1178)
  - List of hymns with numbers, undated (Box 13, Folder 1179)
  - Hymn, "No. 156", undated (Box 13, Folder 1180)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 13, Folder 1181)
  - Johnson, William. Church newsletter, 1935 October 7 (Box 14, Folder 1182)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Unesdala Coll. II (Church affairs)"
  - Letter or note, undated (Box 14, Folder 1183)
  - Voter registration for Jess Pritchett, 1934 June 18 (Box 14, Folder 1184)
  - Recto: Election tally; Verso: Note, undated (Box 14, Folder 1185)
  - Note, undated (Box 14, Folder 1186)
  - English writing practice, undated (Box 14, Folder 1187)
  - Church records, undated (Box 14, Folder 1188)
  - Hummingbird, Jim. Church records, 1940 February (Box 14, Folder 1189)
  - Financial record or election tally, undated (Box 14, Folder 1190)
  - Election tally, undated (Box 14, Folder 1191)
  - Church record, list of names, 1938 August 21 (Box 14, Folder 1192)
  - List of names, 1893 February 23 (Box 14, Folder 1193)
  - Acorn, John B. Sermon notes, bible citations, 1944 May 12 (Box 14, Folder 1194)
  - Postcard to Rev. John B. Acorn, circa 1935 September (Box 14, Folder 1195)
  - Financial record, undated (Box 14, Folder 1196)
  - Financial record, undated (Box 14, Folder 1197)
  - Mulberry Tree Church rededication, 1928 October 28 (Box 14, Folder 1198)
    Translated in Shadow, p. 76
  - Recto: Echota church financial record; Verso: Echota church records, 1925 November 29 (Box 14, Folder 1199)
    Recto: Translated in Shadow, pp. 73-74
  - Unestala. Records of church group meetings at a person's house, 1948 September 19 (Box 14, Folder 1200)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Unestala coll. III"
  - Bird, Jim H. Records of church group meetings, 1948 August 3 (Box 14, Folder 1201)
  - Pritchet, Jess. Records of church group meetings, 1938 June 9 (Box 14, Folder 1202)
  - Records of church group meetings, 1938 January 15 (Box 14, Folder 1203)
  - Adelagatiya. Church treasurer records, undated (Box 14, Folder 1204)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Adelagatiya Coll. 1"
  - Handle, Tom. Letter to brother, 1935 August 21 (Box 14, Folder 1205)
  - List of New Testament citations, undated (Box 14, Folder 1206)
  - List of dates, circa 1934 (Box 14, Folder 1207)
  - Uwedasadi. Meeting records, circa 1934 (Box 14, Folder 1208)
  - List of committee members, 1933 September 12 (Box 14, Folder 1209)
  - Excerpt from administration rules, undated (Box 14, Folder 1210)
  - Adelagatiya. Bible citations, undated (Box 14, Folder 1211)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Adelagatiya Coll. II (Church Records)"
  - Fragment from Robert's Rules of order, undated (Box 14, Folder 1212)
  - Mulberry Tree Church services record, 1935 October 12 (Box 14, Folder 1213)
  - Antioch Church services record, 1936 September 24 (Box 14, Folder 1214)
  - Adelagatiya. Community letter or notice on temperance, undated (Box 14, Folder 1215)
  - Adelagatiya. Letter, 1936 February 27 (Box 14, Folder 1216)
  - Vote or tally notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 1217)
  - Unidentified note, undated (Box 14, Folder 1218)
  - Church or community record, undated (Box 14, Folder 1219)
  - Financial record, 1933 August 7 (Box 14, Folder 1220)
  - Church schedule, minutes, circa 1936 (Box 14, Folder 1221)
    Translated in Shadow, pp. 83-85
  - Possibly fragment of Robert's Rules of order, undated (Box 14, Folder 1222)
  - Financial record, 1957 June 21 (Box 14, Folder 1223)
  - Nofire, Jack. Bible quotations, undated (Box 14, Folder 1224)
  - Echota Sunday School, 1959 August 8 (Box 14, Folder 1225)
    Translated in Shadow, pp. 103-104
  - Medical formula notebook, undated (Box 14, Folder 1226)
  - Letter from secretary of Fourteen Mile Creek church to Jack Nofire, 1955 September 30 (Box 14, Folder 1227)
  - Robbins, Price. Postcard to Jack Nofire, 1957 October 8 (Box 14, Folder 1228)
    Translated in Shadow, p. 103
  - Hymn, translation by Sam Chaudoin of "Marching On," by Will H. Ramsey, undated (Box 14, Folder 1229)
  - Hymn, undated (Box 14, Folder 1230)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand with Cherokee - English name translations; "diyoli huli - Ellis Sanders tige huli - Tim Sanders tlutlu sami - Martin Sam"
  - Hymn with shape singing marks, "105", undated (Box 14, Folder 1231)
  - List of clan names with English translations, undated (Box 14, Folder 1232)
  - Unidentified note on envelope, undated (Box 14, Folder 1233)
  - Rock, Ketcher. Journal or notebook, circa 1946 (Box 14, Folder 1234)
    Translated in Shadow, pp. 99-100
  - Medical formula notebook, undated (Box 14, Folder 1235)
  - Envelope with unidentified text and note with Kilpatrick children's names in Cherokee, circa 1962 (Box 14, Folder 1236)
  - Nofire, Jack. Hymn, "No. 126 in Carols of Love (1954), Stamps-Baxter", undated (Box 14, Folder 1237)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "nuwodvna Hymn Coll."
  - Hymn, "Sitting at the Feet of Jesus in Revival Gems (n.d.), Stamps-Baxter", undated (Box 14, Folder 1238)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "dlanusi doyanida [young beaver] XI"
  - Hider, Sam. Hymn with chorus, undated (Box 14, Folder 1239)
  - Hider, Sam. Hymn with chorus, undated (Box 14, Folder 1240)
  - Walela (Hummingbird). Letter regarding a death, 1956 May 31 (Box 14, Folder 1241)
  - Walela (Hummingbird). Letter regarding a meeting, 1957 April 19 (Box 14, Folder 1242)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Walela Collection (2 letters)"
  - Siquanida. Church records, undated (Box 14, Folder 1243)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Siquanida Secular Coll. (2 pieces)"
  - Siquanida. Church records, undated (Box 14, Folder 1244)
  - Postcards to Mary Belt, circa 1945 (Box 14, Folder 1245)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Mary Belt Coll. (3 postcards)"
  - Church notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 1246)
    Found with note in Jack Kilpatrick's hand, "Unidentified Coll. I Obtained from Sequoyah Leach 1962 July 6 pieces"
  - Church notes, 1945 July 6 (Box 14, Folder 1247)
  - Church notes, 1950 February 12 (Box 14, Folder 1248)